So, now we're going to cover step two.
现在讲解 Offset 函数的第二步操作
We're creating the three scenarios for each of our operating statistics,
我们要针对这三项营业数据分别建立三种情境
because eventually these will feed into the forecast above.
最终会体现到上方的预测结果中
We've created row for each of
这三种情境各占一行
these three scenarios and the actual numbers are based on historical data,
要获得实际数据 需要用到历史数据
which we know as here,
(历史数据列在这个区域) 、
knowledge of the business autonomous,
还有业务分析师的知识背景、
research, and assumptions about the business itself.
调研以及关于公司本身的假设
You would be asking questions like,
在情境中 可能会出现这样的问题 比如
do you expect the revenue growth to stay the same or increase?
你希望收入增长是维持不变还是增加 ?
If so, by how much?
如希望增加 那预期增加多少 ?
Let's walk through each of these,
让我们来看一下每一个情境的情况
base case is the status quo.
基础情境 (base case) 是与现状一致
So, we can plug this in.
要如何预测这个数据呢
So, the average growth was minus six percent.
历史数据中的平均增长率是 -6%
So, you can see that in year two the revenues were lower than year one,
第二年的收入比第一年低
and then they were even further lower in year three.
第三年收入更低
So, this company isn't doing well.
所以 我们可以判断 这家公司的业绩并不理想
So, the revenue growth was minus six percent off of year one,
在收入增长率方面 在第一年基础上减少 6%
and minus four percent off of year two.
在第二年基础上又减少 4%
So, the base case is to just keep the status quo and keep it an average of minus five.
所以 基础情境是与现状一致 即平均增长率为 -5%
The strong case is that you actually reduce this decline and you say,
优势情境 (strong case) 是下降趋势减缓
okay it's going to be minus three.
比如 平均增长率 -3%
The weak case is where it becomes worse.
弱势情境 (weak case) 是负增长情况加剧
So, just for simplicity reason,
我们预测得简单一点
just kept this as minus seven to just show you.
直接预测 -7%
For gross margin, we can see that the gross margin,
在毛利润率方面
we can see has been 0.28 to 0.29.
历史数据是 0.28 到 0.29
So, I'm going to keep this as the base case and then prove it by a percentage 0.02 here.
在基础情境下 维持现状 而在优势情境下则提升了 0.02
Then, the weak case would be where it declined a little bit.
弱势情境则表现出略微下降
Again, this will be based on more about the assumptions about
所以 请记住 进行这些预测时 需要以对公司的假设
the company and having a better business knowledge about the company itself.
以及对公司本身业务情况的了解为基础
Then finally for operating margin,
最后是营业利润率方面
it was 0.07 through 0.05,
历史数据是在 0.05 到 0.07
it ranged in that.
范围内
So, I'm going to keep it at an average of base cases 0.06,
那么 我们就可以预测 在基础情境下 处于该范围的平均值 0.06
strongest 0.08 and 0.09,
优势情境则为 0.08 和 0.09
and then weak cases 0.07 and we'll just keep it there.
弱势情境均为 0.07
So, we have our scenarios mapped out now and we get to step three.
分析完这些情境后 就要进入第三步
I'm just going to pause here and we can watch the next step in the next video.
在下一个视频中 我们将详细讲解第三步操作